SANJAY V

 $+91-9884741300 \diamond$ rajeswarisanjay99@gmail.com LinkedIn \diamond GitHub \diamond Kaggle \diamond Medium

OBJECTIVE

Passionate to become a Principal Researcher and expertise in the field of Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Data Science. Highly qualified Data Engineer and Analytics with experience in the industry. Enjoy creative problem solving and getting exposure on multiple projects, and I would excel in the collaborative environment on which the company prides itself.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechatronics, Chennai Institute of Technology CGPA: 8.74 / 10 2017 - 2021

SKILLS AND TOOLS

Programming Skills: Python, SQL, R

Libraries

Data Mining: Beautiful Soup

Data Processing and Modeling:

Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, SKLearn
Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn
Big Data Tools and Frameworks:

Hadoop, Hive, Flask, Heroku,

AWS (S3, Lambda, Redshift, Glue, Lex, CloudWatch)

VCS, DevOps and Misc Tools: VSCode, Git, Docker, Postman, DB Browser, MongoDB, SQLAlchemy

Data Visualization Tools: Tableau, Highcharts

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Jun 2021 - Present

VueData Technologies Private Limited

 $Chennai,\ India$

- Assisted in pushing the data from Ship Station API to Amazon Redshift using AWS Lambda.
- Performed ETL extract, transform and load data operation from MySQL database to AWS Redshift using AWS Glue jobs.

Software Engineer Intern

Apr 2021 - Jun 2021

VueData Technologies Private Limited

Chennai, India

- Created reports and dashboards for Enterprise Data Analytics, Sales and Marketing Analytics, Customer Segmentation and Product Analytics using Tableau.
- Assisted in pushing the data from Google Analytics to Amazon Redshift using AWS Lambda.
- Built a chatbot which provides customer support such as change in subscription, cancel subscription etc using Amazon Lex and AWS Lambda.

SAP Techno Functional Trainee

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

Kaar Technologies

Chennai, India

• SAP - Function Group, Function Module, Interactive Reports, Tables and View Creation, Module Pool programming and Enhancement.

Machine Learning Research Intern

Jun 2020 - Oct 2020

Tactii (formerly TalentAccurate) - Research Unit

Chennai, India

- ML Snippet collections
- Research areas focused and tools used are mentioned in Certificate of Completion.

PROJECTS

Image Editor and Resizer - Built a project that edits or resizes the image using Wand and displays it in a web application using Flask.

Detection of Kollywood Actor / Actress - Built a ML model to predict kollywood actor / actress with movie characterization as input using Python and SKLearn.

Lane and Speed Detection - Built a project that detects lanes for self-driving vehicles and takes in a video stream for detecting speed of the vehicle using Python and OpenCV.

Drowsiness Detection - Built a project that detects drowsiness and send alert messages to the registered people whenever driver feels drowsy using Python and OpenCV.

Smart Agriculture Nutrients Analysis Robot - Built a project that detects and quantifies the presence of micro and macro nutrients in the soil and provide guidelines about the usage of fertilizers to farmers using Arduino.

SCHOLASTIC AND CO-CURRICULAR ACHIEVEMENTS

- AWS Machine Learning Scholar at Udacity in 2021.
- BRONZE Medal for Kaggle Dataset WikiDeadlink Collection in 2020.
- BRONZE Medal in Kaggle for Glass Type Classification in 2020.
- BRONZE Medal in Kaggle for Stack Overflow (SOF) Prediction in 2020.
- Achieved 99.33 percent accuracy in predicting the lowest price of the products (Hacker Earth Machine Learning Competition) in 2020.
- Big Data Boss Season 1, a ML competition with kollywood dataset lead my team to grab 5th place in 2020.
- New Idea Certificate of Recognition in Google Science Fair Contest in 2018.
- Guided my team at International Robotics League and World Robotics Championship in the field of Innovation Sector and Micro mouse competition in 2018.

POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

• Beta Tester at Cou	irsera.	Apr 2021 -	Present

• Member of Python Software Foundation (PSF).

Mar 2020 - Present

• Member of Open Data Science Conference (ODSC).

Mar 2020 - Present

• Internshala Student Partner (ISP). Sep 2018 - Nov 2018.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft AI Classroom Series Microsoft
- Data Visualization using Tableau Great Learning
- Introduction to R Great Learning
- $\bullet\,$ MLOps (Machine Learning Operations) Fundamentals Google Cloud, Coursera
- How Google Does Machine Learning Google, Coursera
- Launching Into Machine Learning Google, Coursera
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning DeepLearning.AI, Coursera
- AI for Everyone DeepLearning.AI, Coursera
- Introduction to Python and Intermediate Python DataCamp
- SQL Fundamentals SoloLearn